JOSHUA HAYES DAVIDSON

joshua.davidson@network.rca.ac.uk +44 (0) 7765 659 674

Portfolio

www.joshhd.co.uk/portfolio.pdf

ShowReel Password: sr2019 www.vimeo.com/313532603

## **Related Experience**

Oct 2018 - Current

### Lecturer, Westminster Kingsway College

Lesson planning and teaching Interaction Design & Physical comuting classes, in accordance with the UAL Level 3 Media Spec.

July 2017 – June 2018

# **Head Digital Designer, OMVR**

Start-up focused on VR in healthcare. my role as Head Designer included the responsibilities of concept design and art direction for HMD Virtual Reality experiences.

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017

### **Digital Designer, ICUC Social**

Initially designing concepts and developing tone of voice for social media campaigns, Worked to implementation, I also assisted with social media strategy.

September 2015

## Film Producer, EuRathlon

Part of a two-man team directing, filming & editing comprehensive daily coverage of the EuRathlon 10-day robotics competition.

Nov – January 2015

## Digital Designer, Tell Player Ltd.

Majoritively working UX/UI design for mobile. I also produced assets ranging from icons, logos, branding & video. Commissioned by the Acorn Trust to turning an Agatha Christie novel into a mobile digital experience.

July – October 2014

### **Designer, Bristol Robotics Laboratory**

Head Designer attached to two projects funded by the European Union and the Royal Academy of Engineers.

My responsibilities include working from designed concept to artwork in printed projects as well as coding HTML & CSS.

September 2014

# Visual Designer, EARTHFALL

Working to produce and edit live video then and projection mapped during performances.

August 2014

# Set Designer, BBC

Working on set as part of the production team with BBC Wales. My responsibilities included continuity, set organisation & dressing scenes. Additionally, I created graphic posters to promote the films.

July - August 2013

# **Junior Designer, Dirty Design Agency**

My responsibilities included working on live briefs, idea creation, concepts, mocking up prototypes, assembling presentations.

#### About me

Designer with a deep interest in visual image and technological advancement. I'm interested in moving image, digital culture, complex systems, psychology, social politics & environment. I have worked on film production, user experience, user interface, social media campaigns, as well as working with commercial design briefs set to rigorous brand guidelines. I am conscientious, hard-working and driven, enjoying both practical and theoretical challenges. I am a good team player as well as being able to work under my own initiative.

### **Education**

2015–17 | MA Visual Communication, Royal College of Art.

2011–14 | First Class, BA (Hons) Graphic Design, University of the West of England.

2010–11 | Foundation: Art & Design, University of Wales Institute Cardiff

2008–10 A levels: Film, History, Art & Design, Physics. St.Davids College

### **Achievements**

2017 Jan Winning pitch for DAYMARK, creating a network around the coast of the UK. To be installed 2019-2020.

2016 May | Tell Player App nominated for BAFTA Cymru, Technical Achievement.

2015 Sep | EuRathlon Documentary short-listed for 'best picutre' award.

2010 Jun | Short listed for best category photograph at Photomarathon. Cardiff.

# Skill Set

After Effects Illustrator
Arduino Mad Mapper
Cinema 4D Photoshop
Glyphs Premier Pro
HTML & CSS Unity Engine
InDesign Unreal Engine